C'mon, now, don't ignore me!
Hey!
Ow!
Ow! That hurts!
What's the problem? You train every day,
and you still lose to one middle-aged man?
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
Whoa, wait a—
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Letting me get a counter in?
You're getting old, Pops!
I'm about to win by decisio—
Hey, wait! No fair flipping me back over!
Well? Ready to give up?
Ow, ow!
Excuse me, you two...
I'm getting hungry. I'd like
to eat breakfast now.
Whoops...
Sorry about that.
I got a little carried away with
my one-on-one time with Subaru.
You could've started without us.
Why should I do that when the
whole family could eat together?
Yeah, you're right. That's my wife for ya!
Come on, Subaru. Time for breakfast.
I put in extra effort today, just for you.
Wow, Subaru. Your bowl's a forest of green.
Mom, why did you give me so many peas?
It's not good to be picky about your food.
I thought this might be a good
chance to get you over that.
What "chance"? This isn't a
special day or anything.
Very naïve of you, Subaru. Today is...
No, every moment of every day is
a precious, once-in-a-lifetime moment.
That's irrelevant right now.
I'm digging in.
Yes, go right ahead.
I've always wondered... Why the
mix of Japanese and Western dishes?
My favorite thing to put in
miso soup is wakame seaweed,
and I like strawberry jam on my toast.
What are we gonna do with this?
We just keep passing it around...
Well, I hate peas, you know.
And you were trying to make
me stop being picky?!
Don't get the wrong idea, though.
I hate all foods that are tiny and round.
I didn't have any wrong ideas!
If anything, I have even more doubts now!
Okay, then. The husband should
take responsibility for his wife.
Subaru, families that get along as
well as ours are rare these days.
In other words, I hate the same
things you and your mother hate!
This forest of green was never
going to make anyone happy, then!
I'll just make it into something
we all love: pilaf!
I can't even stand to look at it.
Subaru.
Right.
Thank you for breakfast.
My pleasure!
Now, let's get the dishes to the sink,
and we'll race to school to help us digest!
Quit making this a scenario that
ends with me going to school.
I'm sleeping in until noon.
Ow...
Subaru?
It's nothing.
What the hell? Why?
Why do I suddenly feel so weird?
Once it's past eight...
I won't make it to school on time now.
So there's no other choice.
I have no choice...
Why?
That normally calms it down...
Mind if I come in, Subaru?
What's the point of asking if you
come in before I can answer?
There's no need for that between
two guys as tight as you and—
Wait, I guess there is!
Sorry, I forgot you're a teenager!
I'll leave and come back!
I wasn't doing anything!
So?
Well...
Subaru, is there a girl you like?
Are we in middle school now?!
You're no fun.
So, what do you actually want?
Oh, well, you know...
The weather's nice, so...
Let's go have a nice father-son talk outside.
Man, what's with everyone?
They happen to see me on my day off,
and they all assume I lost my job.
Hey, don't make such a gloomy face
on a nice morning like this.
It's your own fault for dragging me out here.
Don't act all suspicious.
I'm not gonna tell you anything scary.
It's more of a father-son subject.
A father-son subject, huh?
Ken, my boy! Haven't seen you in a while.
Oh? Don't tell me that's...
Yep, that's right. He's my son...
Actually, I should say he's my pride and joy.
Ah, so I was right.
He looks so much like you
did when you were...
Actually, no, you don't.
Do you take after your mom?
Uh... Well, a lot of people say I do.
My eyes, especially.
I see.
Hard to believe you're old enough
to have a son that age.
Come to think of it...
Today's Monday, isn't it?
What are you doing out here
with your dad at this hour?
Sorry...
Hey, Subaru!
Sorry about that. We'll stop by
again when we have time to chat.
Ah, sure. Looks like I said
something I shouldn't have.
Apologize to him for me, would you?
You have nothing to apologize for.
It's up to him to deal with it himself now.
Here ya go. A tasty, ice-cold
cola packed with my love.
Don't cluck your tongue at me.
I know how you think.
Ugh, my hand's all sticky now.
Well? Feel better now?
Hard to say.
You look like you're really not feeling well.
Want to go home? I can carry you on my back.
You don't have to do that,
and I don't need to go home.
It'd be the same at home, anyway.
Listen, Subaru... Not to
change the subject, but...
Is there a girl you like?
Subaru...
Huh?
What's up?
Wait... did someone just say my name?
No...
What the heck was that, then?
So? Is there a girl you like?
Why do you keep asking that?
You can stop beating around the bush.
Just come out and ask me
why I didn't go to school.
And here I was trying to
be considerate for once.
Well, that is what I wanted to
talk about, so you're not wrong.
I know it's disrespectful to you and Mom.
There's no need to feel that way.
I do have the vague sense that
you have your reasons for it,
and even if you don't,
I'm prepared to brush it off as
something I can't do anything about.
I don't know about the rest of the world,
but I personally don't believe
school is everything.
I mean, what's the big deal?
Why?
Why did you suddenly decide
to tell me all this today?
It's not like today is a
special day or anything.
It's just... Peas Day.
Well, your bowl was certainly full of them.
I'm not sure why.
I guess the look on your face this
morning seemed a little better.
My face... looked better?
The look on your face.
Your face still looks like a bad guy's,
with those mean eyes you got from your mom.
Nothing about me has changed!
That's how I want it, and that's how I'll—
Hey, you look like you're really in pain!
Are you okay?
Subaru...
It's been rough, hasn't it?
Thank you, Subaru.
Who are you?
For saving me.
What?
What? What? What's going on?
Subaru...
Who are you? Who are you? Who are you?
May the blessing of the spirits be with you.
I think you're much more amazing than me.
Why do you always save me?
Sorry. I'm fine now.
Really? Well, as long as you feel better.
But don't worry me so much, you hear?
Sure. Sorry.
And... about what you asked me...
There is a girl I like.
So... I'll be okay now.
I remember everything now.
What I was so freaked out about,
and why I was cowering in fear.
No, that's not right. I already knew all of it.
I knew, but I was pretending
I didn't see it.
I wanted you and Mom to call out my weakness,
since I was the only one in pain.
To tell me I'm an unbelievably
small person,
an idiot who's never good enough,
and a self-righteous scumbag.
I wanted you both to beat that
into me and make me give up.
I've always had this way of somehow managing
to squeak through anything, you know?
Like in schoolwork and sports.
You're definitely his kid!
But... I don't know when it started...
But I was no longer the best at
things I used to be the best at.
What used to be my "best"
grew smaller and smaller.
I started thinking that it all made no sense.
Working my hardest at school seemed stupid.
And why is being a fast runner
something to brag about?
Making everyone laugh seemed way cooler to me,
and I was way better at it.
You're definitely his kid!
But if I kept that up, it became apparent
that I'd always have to do
something bigger the next time.
I didn't want people to think I was boring.
I thought I could do anything.
I made everyone think I would do anything.
And so the things I did got dumber and dumber.
I was just out of control,
not thinking about anything.
I knew they were a bunch of idiots.
I wanted them to think
that they couldn't have this much
fun if they weren't with me.
That they could regret whatever they wanted,
as long as we spent the boring times
doing pointless crap for fun.
I decided I would set my sights higher.
But the next thing I knew,
I was looking around...
And there was no one left but me.
That's when I finally realized
that there was nothing special about me at all.
You're definitely his kid!
From then on, I just spent all
my time trying not to stand out.
That's how I got through middle school,
then when I got into high school...
I gotta say, I really blew
my high school debut.
But it was bound to happen.
I'd never had any real
relationships up to that point.
High school wasn't gonna be any better.
And then it occurred to me...
I just... didn't want to go to school.
It all just snowballed from there.
One day a week of skipping school
turned into one in every three days,
then every other day...
It didn't take even three months
before I stopped going at all.
But no matter how pathetic I was,
you and Mom still treated me
the same as always.
That's what scared me most of all.
I wanted you to say, "I don't love you."
"I despise you."
"You're not my son."
I wanted you to tell me that and throw me out.
I wanted you to make me give up.
But...
It is easy to give up.
But it doesn't suit you.
I love you, Subaru-kun.
Let's start here,
from square one.
No...
From zero!
Right!
My hero is the greatest in the world!
Subaru...
Father Headbutt!
See that, Subaru? That was my
most loving Father Headbutt,
packed with all my rage!
That was an axe kick!
Nothing about that was a headbutt!
My leg goes up pretty high, huh?
But you know, you're pretty dumb, aren't ya?
H-Huh?
A lot about what you said bothers me,
but you know what's the worst?
You wanted me to hate you,
so you tried to achieve that by
playing hooky? Are you dumb?!
And if you want to get me to throw
you out, pick a more active method!
Who would ditch their own kid just
because he retreated into his shell?!
You're so twisted, you're on the
fast track to being an idiot!
I'd be glad to set you straight
by force if you want...
But it looks like you've already
been knocked down
and stood yourself back up, so there's no need.
Remember what I said? I found a girl I like.
Plus, there's a girl who said she
loved me, despite the way I am.
And neither one of them knows
I'm the son of Natsuki Kenichi.
In their eyes, I'm just Natsuki Subaru.
No, in all of their eyes...
I was Natsuki Subaru.
I finally figured that out.
Well, it took you long enough.
You're just now coming around
to saying all this?
I should whack you.
You just whacked my skull
with your heel a second ago!
Sorry about that.
Still, this was my fault for not realizing
that you thought so highly of your awesome dad.
Sorry I was just too big a part of your life!
I really don't want to admit
that's true, even though it is!
But that took a little of the
weight off my shoulders.
Now all that's left to talk about is
the future. We've only just begun.
Oh, sure. Um, sorry for putting you through—
If you feel sorry, all you gotta do
is take your time making it up to us.
Take good care of your mom
and me when we're old,
my eldest son.
I-I'm sorry.
Subaru?
I'm sorry.
I... I...
I... can't...
I-I'm sorry.
I won't be able to make anything up to
you before... I never see you again.
I'm sorry.
I-I'm sorry, I'm sorry...
I'm so sorry... I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry!
No matter how much time passes,
you're still such a handful, son.
Sheesh.
I still feel like walking a little more,
so I'm going to take the long way home.
Okay. I'll head home myself, then.
Hey, Subaru...
I'm sure you have a lot going on, too,
so there's only one thing I want to say.
Give it your all!
I'm expecting the best from you, son.
Yeah. You can count on me, Dad.
My name is Natsuki Subaru,
son of Natsuki Kenichi!
So I can do anything,
and I will do anything!
'Cause your son's just that awesome!
I know that. You're half me, after all.
The student Natsuki Subaru is complete.
What's it been, about three months?
Oh? Are you nervous?
Want to eat some mayonnaise with me?
Su
I'm not in the mood right now.
I guess not.
You don't actually like mayonnaise
that much, after all.
Huh?
Your dad and I both like it, so you
were just sharing it with us.
Wh-What gives you that—
Then which would you choose:
the world or mayonnaise?
The world, obviously!
You see?
Why do you look so self-satisfied?!
Anyone who picks mayonnaise doesn't
do it because they like mayonnaise!
They just hate the world!
That's true.
Well, I'm gonna head out.
You're leaving for school now?
I'm glad, but... won't that
draw some negative attention?
Why not put off until tomorrow
what can wait until tomorrow?
Your son finally found the motivation
to do something! Don't ruin this!
I'm already too hard on everyone
else and easy on me as it is!
Well, if you really were like that,
it would've meant a lot less trouble for me.
And why are you following me?!
Walking to school with my
mom when I'm trying to
get over being a shut-in is
worse than a game penalty!
I'm not going all the way to school.
Just to the convenience store.
It's been a long time since you
and I walked together, hasn't it?
Has it?
What did you and your dad talk about?
Nothing special.
Just reliving the past and stuff.
Hmm...
And reliving the past made
you want to go to school?
Well, I guess you could say that.
It gave me a chance to look
back on some things, so...
So you've given up on trying to be just
like your father in everything?
You were always a hard worker,
and you could do a lot of
things with minimal effort.
Since your dad was so blindly
into lots of different things,
you had quite a few opportunities.
Exhausting, isn't it?
Mom, just how much do you...
You know, Subaru,
parents watch their kids much
more closely than they realize.
I'm always watching you, too, Subaru.
I gave you a suppository
once when you were little,
so I've even seen your butthole.
Um, sorry, but this was a
nice conversation up until now.
You don't have to say everything you think.
The mayonnaise, too, and your
reasons for not going to school...
If there was anything I could have
done for you, I gladly would have,
but it seemed like nothing
I tried would have worked out.
But...
Someone who isn't me or your father
did something for you, didn't they?
I think that's a wonderful thing.
We should be grateful to them.
Yeah, that's right.
That's why I'm able to walk this path right now.
They're really good people.
I don't deserve them.
But you won't give them to anyone else, right?
You better believe it!
It's not about whether I'm
good enough for them or not.
If I had to give them away, I'd make them mine,
even if I don't deserve them!
I'd just make myself worthy of them after.
Uh-huh...
You're definitely his kid.
Am I... doing all right?
Am I living up to the expectations for his kid?
You don't have to worry.
Half of you is me, after all.
So if you become even half as cool as
your dad, you've filled your quota.
Get half as cool as your dad,
and the other half can just be Subaru.
That means you can just do
your best in your own way.
At least, that's what I think.
In my own way... huh?
That's right.
You can want to be like your mom and dad
as you become Subaru.
Well, I'm heading this way.
Will you be okay on your own?
I'll be fine.
I see.
Well, give it your all, then.
Mom!
There's something I need to do!
So... I won't see you for a long time!
It's kinda far away... so I don't
think I'll be able to keep in touch!
But no matter where I am...
I'll be thinking of you guys!
And I'll never... forget you.
Subaru...
I'll never not want to be your kid anymore...
And I don't want to do anything
that would make me hate myself!
Subaru...
It's okay.
I know what you're trying to say.
You... do?
How?
Well, because I'm your mother, of course.
I'm sorry, Mom.
I was... never able to do anything
for you guys, and now...
We didn't have you because we wanted
you to do something for us.
We had you because we wanted
to do something for you.
I'm... I'm acting like a little kid...
Pathetic...
There's nothing wrong with crying.
You can cry all you want.
As long as you can smile when
you're done, everything will be fine.
What matters isn't how you start
or what happens in the middle.
It's how it ends.
You mean as long as things turn out
okay in the end, nothing else matters?
That's not how I meant for you to take it.
It's a homework assignment from me.
Well... I'm going, then.
Oh, that's right!
Subaru, Subaru! I almost forgot!
Take care.
I will!
Okay.
You arrived much earlier than I expected.
Welcome.
So you've had some time to confront your past.
What did it do for you?
Parent and Child